Guide to the Frey Family Papers 1793-1917 (Bulk 1825-1890) MS 235
New-York Historical Society
Frey Family Papers
1793-1917 (bulk 1825-1890)
New-York Historical Society
MS 235
10.5 Linear feet (25 boxes)
The Frey Family Papers primarily document multiple generations of the Frey and related Ludlow and Van Schaack families of upstate New York and elsewhere. The bulk of the collection is correspondence (16 boxes), detailing family news, health matters, and deaths; opinions on religion, politics, and the Civil War; financial, legal, and property issues and troubles; family history and genealogy.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Portions of the collection that have been microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format and can be made available by Interlibrary loan.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading room for details.
Biographical Note
This collection contains items for over one hundred individuals. See family trees (available at repository) for the Frey, Ludlow, and Van Schaack families for relationships, birth and death dates. These trees were compiled from a variety of sources, including the items in the collection.
Many individuals in this collection had nicknames and used them often in correspondence. The following nicknames are commonly used:
Missing Title
Frey, Adelle Reynolds "Dell"
Frey, Augustus Beardslee "Gus"
Frey, Caroline [b.1868] "Carrie"
Frey, Elizabeth Van Schaack "Betsey"
Frey, Henrietta Swift "Etta"
Frey, Henry A. "Harry"
Frey, John [d.1858] "Johnny"
Frey, Samuel Ludlow "Ludlow," "Lud"
Winne, Caroline Frey G. "Carrie," "Sis"
Winne, Charles K. Jr. "Bopper"
Scope and Content Note
The Frey Family Papers primarily document multiple generations of the Frey and related Ludlow and Van Schaack families of upstate New York and elsewhere. The bulk of the collection is correspondence (16 boxes), detailing family news, health matters, and deaths; opinions on religion, politics, and the Civil War; financial, legal, and property issues and troubles; family history and genealogy. The larger correspondence subseries include letters from Caroline Frey Winne written from army postings in the western United States during the 1870s and 1880s; letters from Samuel Ludlow Frey concerning the family farm and finances; and letters from John Frey regarding financial, legal, and property matters. Letters from Henry A. Frey detail his ongoing financial, familial, and marital difficulties. Various members of the Ludlow family are also represented, presenting their opinions on religion, politics, and current events.
This collection also contains diaries; financial, legal, and property records; genealogies; poetry; ephemera; organizational and educational material; drafts of writings; notes, memoranda, and extracts; newspapers and clippings; sketches; one photograph; and documents relating to a southern gold mine.
The Frey Family Papers support research in the histories of New York State (major locations represented include Palatine Bridge, Oswego, New York City, Albany, Kinderhook); nineteenth century family life and religion; the Civil War; and late nineteenth century western history (letters of Caroline Frey Winne). This collection also supports research in nineteenth century women's history. The letters of Caroline Ludlow Frey, Christina Cantine, Elizabeth Van Schaack Frey, Anna Ludlow, Ellen Ludlow, and Helen Ludlow, for example, discuss family and social lives, health, religion, childrearing, politics, and current events (see subseries descriptions for details). In addition, the Frey Family Papers contain a number of letters written by children. See especially Caroline Frey ["Carrie" b.1868], Helen Frey, John Frey ["Johnny" d.1858], Wallace Jones, and Charles K. Winne, Jr.
Arrangement
Correspondence arranged by sender. See container list for other series arrangements.
The collection is organized into the following seventeen series:
Missing Title
Series I. Correspondence, 1793-1917, undated
Series II. Diaries, 1821-[18]92, undated
Series III. Financial Records, 1799-1912, undated
Series IV. Legal Material, 1799-1865, undated
Series V. Land and Property Records, 1806-1873, undated
Series VI. Genealogical Material, undated
Series VII. Poetry, undated
Series VIII. Ephemera, 1818-[1904], undated
Series IX. Organizational Material, 1880-1911, undated
Series X. Educational Material, 1833-1857, undated
Series XI. Drafts, 1799, 1852, undated
Series XII. Notes, Memoranda and Extracts, 1849-1891, undated
Series XIII. Gold Mine Documents, 1844-1866
Series XIV. Newspapers, Clippings and Reprints, 1860-1907, undated
Series XV. Sketches, undated
Series XVI. Photograph, undated
Series XVII. Fragments, undated
Drafts (documents); Fliers (printed matter); Drawings (visual works); Contracts.; Account books.; Accounts.; Advertisements.; Reports.; Receipts (financial records); Programs (documents).; Poetry.; Memorandums.; Marital conflict.; Legal documents.; New York (State) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Invitations.; Indentures.; Genealogies (histories); Estate inventories.; New York (State) -- Politics and government.; Spiritual journals.; Circulars (fliers).; Notebooks.; Darien (Wis.); Oswego (N.Y.); New York (State) -- Religious life and customs -- 19th century.; Florida -- Description and travel.; Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.).; Indians Of North America -- Wars.; Indians Of North America -- Rites and ceremonies.; Indians Of North America -- Government relations.; Army spouses -- West (U.S.).; Gold mines and mining -- South Carolina.; Family -- New York (State).; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Supplies.; Agriculture -- New York (State) -- Palatine Bridge; Law -- Study and teaching -- New York (State).; Adultery -- United States.; African American children -- Education; Child rearing -- United States.; Diaries.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Divorce -- United States.; Farm life -- New York (State).; Family -- Religious life.; Religious education -- New York (State).; Women -- Religious life -- New York (State).; Gold mines and mining -- North Carolina.; New York (State) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century.; Mohawk River Valley (N.Y.) -- History.; Fort Sidney (Neb.); Clippings (information artifacts); Fort McPherson (Ga.); Fort Washakie (Wyo.); Fort Wadsworth (N.Y.); Benicia Barracks (Calif.); Correspondence.; Ludlow, H. G. (Henry Gilbert), 1797-1867; Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1791-; North Western Insurance Company of Pennsylvania; Sitting Bull, 1831-1890; Spring Street Presbyterian Church (New York, N.Y.); United States. Army -- Military life; United States. Army -- Officers; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 110th (1862-1865); Van Scoyoc family; Winne, Caroline Frey; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.); Cantine, Christina M.; Crazy Horse, approximately 1842-1877; First Presbyterian Church (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.); Frey, Augustus Beardslee; Frey, Caroline Ludlow, 1803-1873; Frey, Henry A., -1885; Frey, Henry I., 1780-1832; Frey, Henry; Frey, John, 1806-1886; Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1833-1924; Herkimer family; Ludlow family
- Series I: Correspondence, 1793-1917, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Sixteen boxes. Arranged alphabetically by sender, into 102 subseries. Letters with multiple authors are filed under the first name to appear. Women, if married, are filed under their final surname.
  - Subseries 1. Letters sent, A
    - Letters sent, A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2. Backus, E.F., 1833-1836
    Letters concern land purchase, property.
    - Letters sent, Backus, E.F., 1833-1836 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3. Baldwin family, 1793-1900
    Letters concern family news, deaths, and history.
    - Letters sent, Baldwin family, 1793-1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4. Ball, Amy, 1899-1900
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey regarding family history and genealogy.
    - Letters sent, Ball, Amy, 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5. Ball, Jane G., 1861-1898
    Letters concerning family matters.
    - Letters sent: Ball, Jane G., 1861-1898 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6. Ball, Margaret, 1859-1878, undated
    Letters regarding family matters, health, current events.
    - Letters sent: Ball, Margaret, 1859-1878, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 7. Barber, Edwin A., 1881-1912
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey regarding pottery, china, stoneware.
    - Letters sent: Barber, Edwin A., 1881-1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 8. Beardslee, Augustus, 1829, 1834-1838, 1859-1863
    Letters concerning financial matters, family (esp. the deaths of Philip Frey and Elizabeth Frey Beardslee), family strife.
    - Letters sent: Beardslee, Augustus, 1829, 1834-1838, 1859-1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 9. Beardslee, Elizabeth Frey, 1822-1837, undated
    Letters regarding family, local news, deaths of friend, brother, and child, medical and health matters, child rearing and weaning.
    - Letters sent: Beardslee, Elizabeth Frey, 1822-1837, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 10. Beardslee, Ethel, 1910-1913, undated
    Letters concern family news, books read, travels.
    - Letters sent: Beardslee, Ethel, 1910-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 11. Beekman, J.P. [John], 1838-1839
    Letters regarding finances, wool.
    - Letters sent: Beekman, J.P., 1838-1839 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 12. Beekman, Lydia, 1830-1866, undated
    Letters concern family matters, especially condolence letters for the deaths of Henry Van Schaack Frey, Henry I. Frey, Elizabeth Frey Beardslee, and Phebe Ludlow.
    - Letters sent: Beekman, Lydia, 1830-1866 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 13. Beekman, Thomas, 1835-1863
    Letters regarding property, finances, family deaths.
    - Letters sent: Beekman, Thomas, 1835-1863 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 14. Bishop, John C., 1855-1856
    Letters Johnny Frey and Samuel Ludlow Frey concerning school, penmanship, holidays, alcohol, farm life, weather, and politics.
    - Letters sent: Bishop, John C., 1855-1856 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 15. Booth, Emma L., 1883-1898, undated
    Travel letters from Italy, Scotland.
    - Letters sent: Booth, Emma L., 1855-1856 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 16. Briggs, B.F., 1866-1867
    Letters to Henry A. Frey regarding gold mining ventures in the Carolinas, especially at King's Mountain, N.C.
    - Letters sent: Briggs, B.F., 1866-1867 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 17. Letters sent, B
    - Letters sent: B (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 18. Cantine, Christina, 1821-1852, undated
    Letters to Caroline Ludlow Frey regarding courtship, friendship, local gossip, religion, social news, local and family deaths.
    - Letters sent: Cantine, Christina, 1821-1829 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Cantine, Christina, 1836-1852, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 19. Conkling family, 1813, 1826, 1845-1864, 1881
    Letters from Conkling family members regarding family matters, politics. Includes:
    Alfred (1813, 1826, 1848, 1849), Alfred R. (1912), Aurelian (1845-1861), Harriette (1861-1881), Roscoe (1854, 1864).
    - Letters sent: Conkling family, 1813, 1826, 1845-1864, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 20. Cox family, 1833, 1854-1856
    Includes letters from Henry F. Cox, including two lengthy letters from abroad (Syria and Egypt, 1856, 1857) that describe his travels throughout the Mid East and down the Nile River. There are also letters from Margaret and Seraphine Cox.
    - Letters sent: Cox family, 1833, 1854-1856 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 21. Letters sent, C
    - Letters sent: Ca-Cl (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: Co-Cu (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 22. Davies, Henry E., 1825-1870
    Letters, mostly to John Frey, concerning the Davies family, romantic advice, religion, Frey's financial matters, the Civil War.
    - Letters sent: Davies, Henry E., 1825-1870 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 23. Deuel, F. Dygert, 1902-1904
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey regarding Herkimer, Dygert and Deuel family genealogies, New York State history.
    - Letters sent: Deuel, F. Dygert, 1902-1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 24. Letters sent, D
    - Letters sent: D (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 25. Letters sent, E
    - Letters sent: E (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 26. Frey, Adelle Reynolds, 1866, 1872-1880, undated ["Dell"]
    Letters concerning the family farm, weather, family news, health.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Adelle, 1866, 1872-1880, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 27. Frey, Augustus B., 1851-1883, 1903, 1917, undated ["Gus"]
    Letters to various family members dealing with family news, his work in the insurance industry, politics (particularly the election of 1860 and his enthusiasm over Lincoln), New York State excursions, the Civil War (Frey joined a Zouaves regiment, the 110th NYSV, in the Union Army summer of 1862), job prospects after the war, weather.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Augustus B., 1851-1862 July (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Augustus B., 1862 Sept.-1871 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Augustus B., 1873-1883, 1903, 1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 28. Frey, Caroline Ludlow, 1813-1872, undated
    Letters to her various family members, children and husband concerning family matters, deaths, religion, health and ailments, advice to children, sewing.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow, 1813-1862 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow, 1862 Nov.-1872 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow (to Caroline Frey Winne), Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Caroline Ludlow, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 29. Frey, Caroline, 1873-1886 ["Carrie"]
    Mostly childhood letters to her grandfather concerning activities on the farm. Also letters from Wells College, Aurora, NY, describing her studies there.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Carrie, 1874-1886 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 30. Frey, Elizabeth Van Schaack, 1824-1833, undated ["Betsey"]
    Letters (most to her son John) offering advice, and detailing family news, her religious convictions, local gossip, and the deaths of three of her children.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Elizabeth Van Schaack, 1824-1833, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 31. Frey, George H., 1873-1881
    Letters (most from Springfield, OH) regarding family news and deaths (particularly his father, wife, and children), family history, politics (esp. the 1876 election and Conkling), Custer, and other contemporary events.
    - Letters sent: Frey, George H., 1873-1881 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 32. Frey, Helen, [1878]-1882, undated
    Childhood letters about the farm, family.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Helen, [1878]-1882, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 33. Frey, Henrietta Swift, 1875-1882 ["Etta"]
    Letters concerning family news, her children's activities.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henrietta, 1875-1882 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 34. Frey, H[enry], 1847-1864
    Letters from Darien, WI, promoting Wisconsin and detailing local life, particularly farming, the railroad. Also discusses the family, health, weather, disease and death, finances, religion, politics (particularly the Republican Party and Roscoe Conkling), the impending secession, and the Civil War.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry ["H."], 1847-1864 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 35. Frey, Henry A., 1854-1884, undated ["Harry"]
    Letters to family members (most from Cleveland, Chicago, and Indiana) regarding family matters, his involvement in coal dealing, various entrepreneurial schemes, continual financial troubles, his attempts to enlist in the Union army, involvement in the Civil War, and in a gold mining venture at King's Mountain, NC. Frey also discusses familial discord, his debts to family members, accusations of impropriety, the dissolution of his marriage, and his emotional troubles. There is a gap in the letters from 1864 to 1866.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1854-1858 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1859-1860 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1861-1862 July (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1862 Aug.-1873 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1874-1878 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1879 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1879-1884, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 36. Frey, Henry A. [probably son of Augustus B. Frey], 1912
    One letter about the birth of his son.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry A., 1912 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 37. Frey, Henry I., 1820-1830, undated
    Letters (most to son John) regarding family and farm news, health, land sales, local news.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry I., 1824-1828, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 38. Frey, Henry Van Schaack, 1824-1828
    Letters describing his school and fellow students, travels in New York State, future plans.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Henry Van Schaack, 1824-1828 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 39. Frey, J.W., 1858-1859
    Letters about family history, the death of his son.
    - Letters sent: Frey, J.W., 1858-1859 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 40. Frey, John [1806-1886], 1825-1886, undated
    Early letters detail his schooling, legal studies, his religious conversion at the age of twenty, and his 1828 marriage to Caroline Ludlow. In late1829, Frey accompanied his brother Henry to St. Augustine, FL, where the latter hoped to find respite from his lung ailment. Letters from Florida describe local population, food, Henry's health and subsequent death in early 1830. Frey's letters from 1830 to 1865 concern his finances, family, legal matters, property and land sales, the farm and planting, limestone and willow trees, family strife with the Beardslees, and the Civil War. There is a gap in the letters from 1845 to 1850, and from 1865 to 1872. After 1872, and a move to Hoboken, N.J., the letters concern the death of his wife (1873), his job at the Custom House, New York City, grandchildren, family news and health. There is also a gap from 1874 to 1877.
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1825-1827 May (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1827 June-1829 Oct (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1829 Nov-1830 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1831-1844 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1850-1858 Feb (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1858 June-1860 June (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1860 July-1866 May (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1861 June-1862 April (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1862 June-1865 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1872-1878 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1879-1886 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 41. Frey, John ["Johnny" d. 1858], 1856-1857
    Letters about farm activities, weather.
    - Letters sent: Frey, John, 1856-1857 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 42. Frey, Mary C., 1876-[1880]
    Letters concern the dissolution of her marriage to Henry A. Frey, and finances.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Mary C., 1876-[1880] (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 43. Frey, Philip, 1834
    One letter to his mother concerning the family.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Philip, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 44. Frey, Philip R., 1822
    One letter to his son about family matters.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Philip R., 1822 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 45. Frey, Samuel C., 1852-1876
    Most letters are written from Decatur, AL, and detail family matters and history; opinions on the Civil War, Southern and national politics; local customs, gardening, weather, farming, keeping chickens, and cotton.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel C., 1852-1876 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 46. Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1850-1917, undated ["Ludlow," "Lud"]
    Early letters written from school in Poughkeepsie detail his studies, local events, family news (esp. Ludlow family), weddings and social events, dental procedures, and weather. Later letters from Palatine Bridge discuss the family's financial troubles, deaths, land sales, the Civil War, farming and winemaking, and health. There is a gap in the letters from 1865 to 1872. After 1872, his letters continue to describe finances and debt, farming, health, and local news. Also under discussion are his mother's death in 1873, other deaths, politics, the railroad, Henry A. Frey's continual financial troubles, digging for Indian relics, articles written and submitted for publication, and family news. There is another gap in the letters from 1883 to 1895. Later letters concern family and local history, and a dispute with the New York Central & Hudson River Co. over a fence and drainage on Frey property.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1850-1861 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1862-1865 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1872-1873 Apr (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1873 May-1874 Apr. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1874 May-1875 June (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1875 July-1876 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1877-1878 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1879 Jan-Oct (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1879 Nov-1880 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1881 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1882-1883, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, 1895-1917 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Frey, Samuel Ludlow, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 47. Frey, Sue R., 1875-1878
    Letters from Racine, WI, regarding family news and history, health, deaths, women's rights.
    - Letters sent: Frey, Sue R., 1875-1878 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 48. Letters sent, F
    - Letters sent: F (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 49. Greene, Annie, [19]12-1915
    Letters concerning New York State history.
    - Letters sent: Greene, Annie, [19]12-1915 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 50. Greene, Estelle, 1911-[1913], undated
    Letters about Seattle, social events, travel plans.
    - Letters sent: Greene, Estelle, 1911-[1913] (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 51. Greene, Helen, 1912
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey requesting that he speak before the Montgomery County Historical Society on Sir William Johnson.
    - Letters sent: Greene, Helen, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 52. Greene, Nelson, 1913-1917
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey regarding New York State history, and Frey's writings including "The Story of Our River" and "The Mohawks."
    - Letters sent: Greene, Nelson, 1913-1917 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 53. Letters sent, G
    - Letters sent: G (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 54. Havens, Paul E., 1898-1912
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey from Leavenworth, KS about family history and news, travels.
    - Letters sent: Havens, Paul E., 1898-1912 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 55. Hees, A., 1857-1876
    Letters, presumably to John Frey, containing family and local news, deaths, politics, health, financial matters, the death of Hees' wife, and Frey's legal troubles with George A. Johnson.
    - Letters sent: Hees, A., 1858-1859 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 56. Letters sent, H